Douglas Southall Freeman Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Douglas Southall Freeman Papers 1900-1979 (bulk 1934-1954)
MSS21501
Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1886-1953
70,000 items
242 containers plus 2 oversize
96 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Biographer, editor, educator, and lecturer. Correspondence, diaries, manuscripts and proofs of books and other works, articles, speeches, notebooks, source materials largely relating to the American Revolution and Civil War, bibliographical material, clippings, printed material, memorabilia, maps, photographs, and other papers relating primarily to Freeman's biographical and historical research and writing.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Boatwright, Frederic William, 1868-1951--Correspondence.; Byrd, Harry F. (Harry Flood), 1887-1966--Correspondence.; Darden, Colgate W. (Colgate Whitehead), 1897-1981--Correspondence.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969--Correspondence.; Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1886-1953.; Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1886-1953. George Washington: a biography. 1948-1957.; Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1886-1953. Lee's lieutenants: a study in command. 1946.; Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1886-1953. R.E. Lee: a biography. 1934-1935.; Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1886-1953. South to posterity: an introduction to the writings of Confederate history. 1939.; Glasgow, Ellen, 1873-1945--Correspondence.; Lee, Robert E. (Robert Edward), 1807-1870.; Malone, Dumas, 1892-1986--Correspondence.; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959--Correspondence.; Nevins, Allan, 1890-1971--Correspondence.; Robertson, A. Willis (Absalom Willis), 1887-1971--Correspondence.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972--Correspondence.; Washington, George, 1732-1799.
Subjects
American newspapers--Virginia--Richmond.
Places
Confederate States of America--History.; Richmond (Va.)--Politics and government.; Richmond (Va.)--Social conditions.; Richmond (Va.)--Social life and customs.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; United States--Social conditions--20th century.; United States--Social life and customs--20th century.; Virginia--Politics and government--20th century.; Virginia--Social conditions.; Virginia--Social life and customs.
Titles
Richmond news leader.
Occupations
Authors.; Biographers.; Editors.; Educators.; Lecturers.
Provenance
The papers of Douglas Southall Freeman, biographer, editor, teacher, and lecturer, were given to the Library of Congress by his wife, Inez Freeman, in 1955.
Additional Guides
A press release on the Douglas Southall Freeman papers was issued by the Library of Congress on Aug. 22, 1955; an acquisitions note on them appeared in the Library's Information Bulletin 14, no. 33 (August 15, 1955): 3-4; and they were described in the Library of Congress Quarterly Journal of Current Acquisitions 13, no. 3 (May 1956): 156. In 1960 the Library published Douglas Southall Freeman, a Register of His Papers in the Library of Congress.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Douglas Southall Freeman are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1886, May 16 Born, Lynchburg, Va.
1904 A.B., Richmond College, Richmond, Va.
1908 Ph.D., Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Md.
1914 Married Inez Virginia Goddin
1915 Commissioned by Scribner's Sons to write biography of Robert E. Lee
1915 1949 Editor, Richmond News Leader
1934 1935 Published R. E. Lee: A Biography. New York: Scribner's. 4 vols.
1934 Awarded Pulitzer Prize Rector and president, Board of Trustees of the University of Richmond, Richmond, Va.
1934 1941 Taught journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1936 Lectured at Army War College
1939 Published The South to Posterity; An Introduction to the Writings of Confederate History. New York: Scribner's
1942 1944 Published Lee's Lieutenants: A Study in Command. New York: Scribner's. 3 vols.
1948 1957 Published George Washington, a Biography. New York: Scribner's. 7 vols. (vol. 7 by John A. Carroll and Mary W. Ashworth)
1953, June 13 Died, Richmond, Va.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Douglas Southall Freeman (1886-1953) span the years 1900-1979, with the bulk of the material dating between 1934 and 1954. The papers relate to nearly all of Freeman's activities other than his work as newspaper editor. The greater portion of the papers relates to his speeches, articles, lectures, and particularly to his books. There are manuscripts of many of his speeches and articles and nearly complete manuscripts and working papers for his major writings, including his biographies of Robert E. Lee and George Washington. His correspondence also reveals his interest in social and political affairs in Richmond, in Virginia, and across the nation. The papers are organized into nine series: Diaries, Journals, and Related Material; General Correspondence; Special Correspondence and Biographical File; Material Relating to the Death of Freeman; Speech, Article, and Book File; Research File; Miscellany; Addition, and Oversize.
Significant in the collection are transcripts, photostats, maps, and source material that Freeman used in the writing of his books. Notes and bibliographies are also included. Newspaper clippings, photographs, printed matter, programs, and other memorabilia complete the collection.
The papers reveal an extensive correspondence between Freeman and prominent historians, literary figures, politicians, educators, and military leaders including Frederic William Boatwright, Harry Flood Byrd, Colgate W. Darden, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Ellen Anderson Gholson Glasgow, Dumas Malone, George C. Marshall, Allan Nevins, A. Willis Robertson, and Harry S. Truman. In addition there is business, professional, and social correspondence.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in nine series:
Diaries, Journals, and Related Material, 1902-1953
General Correspondence, 1900-1954
Special Correspondence and Biographical File, 1904-1954
Material Relating to the Death of Freeman, 1953-1954
Speech, Article, and Book File, 1908-1954
Research File, 1908-1954
Miscellany, 1907-1954
Addition, 1917-1979
Oversize
Container List
- Diaries, Journals, and Related Material, 1902-1953 (Box 1-3)
  Diaries, and journals of trips with related correspondence, notes, drafts of articles, and photographs.
  Arranged by type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Diaries (Box 1)
    - 1902
    - 1907
    - 1918-1922, (5 vols.)
    - 1936-1939, (4 vols.)
    - 1940-1946, (7 vols.)
    - 1947-1953 (Box 2)
  - Journals (Box 3)
- General Correspondence, 1900-1954 (Box 4-120)
  Letters sent and received.
  Arranged chronologically by periods of one or several years with alphabetical arrangement by name of correspondent or subject within a given period. These are Freeman's working files essentially as he used them. Strict chronology is not always followed; for example, the Library of Congress file for 1951 has material for several years within it.
  - 1900-1916 (Box 4)
  - 1917-1926 (Box 5)
    - “A” miscellaneous, 1921-1926, (2 folders)
    - “B” miscellaneous, 1917-1926, (2 folders)
    - Bryan, John Stewart, 1921-1926, (3 folders)
    - Bradford, Gamaliel, 1924-1925
    - Bridges, Robert, 1925-1926
    - Burlingame, E. L., 1917-1920
    - Freeman, Allen, 1918-1926, (5 folders) (Box 6)
    - “G” miscellaneous, 1919-1926, (2 folders)
    - “H” miscellaneous, 1918-1926, (2 folders)
    - Hampton Gardens, 1924
    - House, 1924-1925, (2 folders)
    - Income tax, 1917-1926
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - “J-K” miscellaneous, 1926, (2 folders)
    - “L” miscellaneous, 1918-1926, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - “M” miscellaneous, 1917-1926, (3 folders)
    - “N” miscellaneous, 1918-1926
    - “O” miscellaneous, 1922-1925
    - “P” miscellaneous, 1919-1926, (3 folders)
    - Poe Shrine, 1924-1948, (2 folders)
    - Potts, Allen, 1918-1924
    - “R” miscellaneous, 1918-1926, (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - “S-T” miscellaneous, 1921-1926, (7 folders)
    - “W” miscellaneous, 1918-1926, (3 folders)
    - “Y” miscellaneous, 1921-1926
    - Yale, Stephenson N. W., 1927-1929
  - 1927-1930 (Box 9)
    - “A” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Alderman, E. A., 1927-1929
    - Anderson, Henry W., 1927-1930
    - Andrew, Matthew Page, 1930
    - “Ba-Bh” miscellaneous, 1928-1930
    - Battlefield guides, 1930
    - “Bi-Bq” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Blackwell, R. E., 1929
    - Boat, sail, 1930
    - Boatwright, Frederick William, 1927-1930
    - “Br-Bt” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Bradford, Gamaliel, 1927-1929
    - Brown, William M., 1927-1929
    - Bryan, J. S., 1927-1930, (3 folders)
    - “Bu-Bz” miscellaneous, 1929-1930
    - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1927-1928
    - Byrd, Harry Flood, 1927-1930, (4 folders)
    - Carrington, Tazewell M., 1927-1930 (Box 10)
    - Carnegie trip, 1927
    - Carson, W. E., 1928-1930
    - Carter, Spencer L., 1928
    - “Ca-Cg” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Chase, Enoch A., 1928-1930
    - Chandler, J. A. C., 1927-1928
    - “Ch-Cq” miscellaneous, 1927-1930, (2 folders)
    - Cooke, Giles B., 1927-1930
    - Cowardin, Sam P., Jr., 1928
    - “Cr-Cz” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Crane, Richard, 1927-1930
    - Cutchins, John A., 1928
    - “Da-Dn” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Debutts, Mrs. Hunter, 1930
    - “Do-Dz” miscellaneous, 1927
    - DeGrange, J. William, 1919-1930
    - Dickenson, Margaret, 1930
    - Drumm, Stella, 1927-1929
    - “E” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Eckenrode, H. J., 1927-1930
    - “Fa-Fn” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Farman, E. E., 1929-1930
    - First and Merchants Bank, 1926-1930
    - Fleming, W. M., 1927-1929
    - “Fo-Fz” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Freeman, Allen W., 1927-1930
    - Freeman, D. S., 1928-1929
    - Freeman, Inez (wife), 1929
    - Freeman, W. B., 1927-1928
    - “Ga-Gz” miscellaneous, 1928-1930, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Glass, Carter, 1928
    - Grinnan, D. C., 1927-1930
    - “Haa-Hal” miscellaneous, 1928-1930
    - “Ham-Hn” miscellaneous, 1927-1930, (2 folders)
    - Harmon, Raymond, 1930
    - Harrison, Fairfax, 1927-1930
    - Hay, T. R., 1927-1930
    - Hill, A. P., and John Bell Hood, Generals, 1929
    - “Ho-Ht” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Horsley, J. S., 1929-1930
    - “Hu-Hz” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Hughes, Robert M., 1927-1928
    - Humphreys, Milton W., 1927
    - Hunton, Eppa, Jr., 1928-1930
    - “I” miscellaneous, 1928-1929
    - Income tax, 1927-1929, (2 folders)
    - “J” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Jewett, Henry C., 1928
    - Johnston, J. Ambler, 1928-1930
    - “Ka-Kz” miscellaneous, 1927-1930, (2 folders)
    - Keyserling, Herman, 1927
    - “La-Ld” miscellaneous, 1927-1930 (Box 12)
    - Lawyers Title Insurance Co., 1927-1928
    - “Le-Ln” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Lee, G. T., 1927-1930
    - Lee, George B. L., 1929
    - Lee, Robert E., 1927-1930, (3 folders)
    - “Lo-Lz” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Lovell, Mrs. W. S., 1928-1930
    - “Ma-Mb” miscellaneous, 1927-1930, (3 folders)
    - Mackall, Leonard L., 1928-1930
    - “Mc-Md” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - McDonald, Hunter, 1927-1929
    - Minis, J. F., 1927-1930
    - “Me-Mz” miscellaneous, 1927-1930, (2 folders)
    - Mortgage, 1108 Floyd Avenue, Richmond, 1920-1926
    - “N” miscellaneous, 1928-1930
    - “O” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - “Pa-Ph” miscellaneous, 1927-1930 (Box 13)
    - Perkins, Maxwell E., 1927-1930
    - Phillips, Charles H., 1927-1930 See also Container 33, same heading
    - “Pi-Pz” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Pitt, R. H., 1928-1930
    - Pollard, John Garland, 1928-1930
    - Porter, Mary S., 1919-1927
    - Potts, Allen, 1927-1929, (3 folders)
    - Powell, Mrs. D. V. M., 1928-1930
    - Powell, Mary S., 1928
    - “Ra-Rn” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Radio Bible class, 1929-1930
    - Receipts, 1927-1929
    - Rhoads, W. S., 1927-1930
    - Rich, Edgar J., 1927-1928
    - Richmond, University of
      - General, 1928-1930
      - Committee on Election of Trustees, 1928-1930, (2 folders)
    - “Ro-Sd” miscellaneous, 1927-1930, (3 folders)
    - Scott, Frederic W., 1927-1930
    - Scott & Stringfellow, Richmond, 1928
    - “Se-Sj” miscellaneous, 1927-1928
    - Sites, Maud G., 1927-1930, (3 folders)
    - “Sk-Ss” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - “St-Sz” miscellaneous, 1927-1930 (Box 14)
    - Stanard, William G., 1927-1930
    - Stewens, Ferderick A., 1927
    - Stuart, Albert, clerk of Westmoreland, 1928
    - Sully, Julia, 1928-1929
    - Swanson, Claude A., 1928-1930
    - “T” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Tax receipts, 1918-1930
    - Taylor, Charles H., 1928-1930
    - Taylor, W. H., III, 1930
    - Trinkle, E. Lee, 1928-1929
    - Thom, William Taylor, 1927
    - “U-V” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - “Wa-Wh” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Weddel, A. W., 1927-1930
    - 2700 West Grace Street, Richmond, 1928-1929
    - Weyers, W. B., the Hague, 1928
    - “Wi-Wz” miscellaneous, 1927-1930
    - Wickham, Henry T., 1927-1929
    - Will (draft), 1928
    - Williams, Ennion G., 1927-1930
    - Wright, B. F., 1930
    - Wyman, Mrs. John C., 1928
    - “X-Z” miscellaneous, 1928-1930
  - 1931-1933 (Box 15)
    - “A” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Anderson, H. W., 1930-1933
    - Amory, C. P., 1932-1933
    - Automobiles, 1931-1933
    - “Ba-Bh” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Battlefield parks, 1933
    - “Bi-Bq” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Blackwell, R. E., 1931 See also same container, “Bi-Bq”
    - Boatwright, Frederick William, 1931-1933
    - Boats, 1930-1933, (2 folders)
    - Bottom, R., 1933
    - Boyd, William K., 1932-1933, (2 folders)
    - “Br-Bt” miscellaneous, 1931
    - Bright, J. F., 1931-1933
    - Bronson, Sherlock, 1933
    - Bryan, J. S., 1931-1933
    - Bryan, Joseph, III, 1933
    - “Bu-Bz” miscellaneous, 1931
    - Burgess, L. A., 1931-1933
    - Byrd, Harry Flood, 1931-1933
    - “Ca-Cg” miscellaneous, 1931-1933 (Box 16)
    - Cabler, Edgie, 1932-1933
    - Calrow, C. J., 1932-1933
    - Cannon, J. J., 1931
    - Carrington, T. M., 1931-1932
    - Carson, W. E., 1931-1933
    - Carter, Robert H., 1932-1933
    - Campbell, H. D., 1933
    - “Ch-Cn” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Chandler, J. A. C., 1931
    - Chilton, R. H., 1931
    - “Co-Cq” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Confederate reunion, 1932
    - Confederate Museum, 1933
    - Cooke, G. B. and Miss K., 1931-1933
    - Couper, William, 1932-1933
    - “Cr-Cz” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Crane, Richard, 1931-1932
    - Cunningham, Richard E., 1931
    - “Da-Dn” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - De Butts, Mrs. Hunter, 1932-1933
    - DeGrange, J. W., 1931
    - Dictionary of American Biography, 1931-1933
    - “Do-Ds” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - “E” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Edwards, T. C., 1932
    - “Fa-Fn” miscellaneous, 1931-1933 (Box 17)
    - First and Merchants Bank, 1931-1933, (3 folders)
    - Fitzgerald, Mary Maury, 1931
    - “Fo-Fz” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Freeman, Allen W., 1931-1932
    - Freeman, W. B., 1931
    - Freeman, H. G., 1931-1933
    - Freeman, Inez, 1931-1933
    - Freeman, Mary Tyler, school and college, 1931-1933
    - “Ga-Gk” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Gaines, F. P., 1933
    - “Gl-Gz” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Glass, Carter, 1933
    - Goodwin, William A. R., 1932
    - Grant, Ulysses S., 1932
    - Gray, Garland, 1933
    - Grinnan, Henry, 1931-1933
    - “Haa-Hd” miscellaneous, 1931-1933, (2 folders)
    - Harmon, Mrs. E. W., 1932-1933
    - Harrison, F., 1933
    - “He-Hn” miscellaneous, 1932-1933
    - “Ho-Ht” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Houston, C. H., 1933
    - Hodges, LeRoy, 1932
    - Horsley, Dr., 1931-1933
    - Hough, Tilghman, 1932
    - “Hu-Hz” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Hughes, R. M., 1933
    - “I” miscellaneous, 1931-1932 (Box 18)
    - Income tax, 1929-1932
    - “J” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Jaffe, L. I., 1932
    - Johnston, J. A., 1931-1933
    - “Ka-Ln” miscellaneous, 1931-1933, (4 folders)
    - Landers, H. L., 1931-1933
    - Lee, R. E., 1931-1933, (3 folders)
    - Lee, Fitzhugh, 1931-1932
    - Lee, G. B., 1932
    - Lee, G. T., Sr., 1931
    - “Lo-Lz” miscellaneous, 1933
    - “Ma-Mb” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Mapel, William L., 1933
    - “Mc-Mn” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - McIlwane, H. R., 1931
    - Meade, Robert D., 1931
    - Milbourne, H. C., 1933
    - “Mo-Mz” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Montague, Jeffry, 1931-1932, (2 folders)
    - Morley, Felix, 1933
    - Morrissett, C. H., 1931
    - “N” miscellaneous, 1931-1933 (Box 19)
    - News Leader Current Events Club, 1931
    - Noell, R. J., Sr., 1932
    - Nolting Co., 1927-1933, (2 folders)
    - “O” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - “Pa-Ph” miscellaneous, 1931-1932
    - Patterson, A. W., 1931
    - Perkins, Maxwell E., 1931-1933, (2 folders)
    - “Pi-Pz” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Pitt, R. H., 1933
    - Pollard, J. G., 1931-1933
    - “Q” miscellaneous, 1932
    - “Ra-Rn” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Ratcliffe-Guza case, 1931
    - Richmond, University of
      - General, 1931
      - Pensions, 1931
      - Centennial celebration, 1931-1932
    - Rhoads, W. S., 1931-1933
    - “Ro-Rz” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Russel, T. H., 1933
    - “Sa-Ss” miscellaneous, 1931-1933, (4 folders) (Box 20)
    - Sanger, W. T., 1931-1933
    - Sheib, S. H., 1932-1933
    - Sites, Maud G., 1931-1933
    - Smith, H. M., Jr., 1931-1933
    - Southern Historical Society, 1931
    - “St-Sz” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Stanard, W. G., 1931-1932
    - Stearnes, Mrs. F. D., 1933
    - Stringfellow, G. F., 1932
    - Stone, E. L., 1933
    - Stuart, E. T., 1932
    - Sully, Julia, 1932-1933
    - Swanson, C. A., 1933
    - “T” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Tax receipts, 1931-1933
    - Taylor, Charles H., 1931-1933
    - Taylor, R. L., 1932-1933
    - “U-V” miscellaneous, 1933
    - “Wa-Wh” miscellaneous, 1931-1933
    - Weddell, Alexander W., 1931-1933
    - Wheeler, Mrs., 1932
    - White, Walter, 1933
    - Whittet, R. M., 1932-1933
    - Whitty, J. H., 1933
    - “Wi-Wz” miscellaneous, 1931-1932
    - Wickham, H. T., 1931-1933, (2 folders)
    - Williams (general), 1933
    - Willoughby Beach, 1931-1933, (2 folders)
    - “X-Z” miscellaneous, 1931
  - 1934-1936 (Box 21)
    - “A” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Ackerman, Carl W., 1934-1936, (2 folders)
    - Anderson, H. W., 1934
    - Andrews, Charles M., 1934-1935
    - Armes, Ethel, 1935-1936
    - Ashworth, O. O., 1934-1936
    - Automobiles, 1934
    - “Ba-Bh” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Baker, Newton Diehl., 1935
    - “Bi-Bq” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Boatwright, Frederick William, 1934-1936
    - “Br-Bt” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Brucker, Herbert, 1934-1936
    - Bryan, J. S., 1934-1936, (3 folders)
    - Bryan, R. C., 1934
    - Bryan, Tennant, 1936
    - Byrd, Harry Flood, 1933-1936
    - “Bu-Bz” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - “Ca-Cq” miscellaneous, 1934-1936, (3 folders) (Box 22)
    - Coker, D. R., 1935-1936
    - Columbia University lectures, 1934-1936
    - Cooke, Giles B., 1934-1936
    - “Cr-Dn” miscellaneous, 1934-1936, (2 folders)
    - Darrow, Whitney, 1934-1936
    - Davis, Jackson, 1935-1936
    - Devoy, E., 1934-1936
    - Dickerson, A. I., 1935
    - “Do-Fn” miscellaneous, 1934-1936, (3 folders)
    - Farnsworth, C. S., 1934-1935
    - First and Merchants Bank, 1934
    - Flags, 1941-1943
    - Frank, Mrs. Glenn, 1936
    - “Fo-Fz” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Freeman, A. W., 1934-1936
    - Freeman, H. G., 1933-1935
    - Freeman, Mary Tyler, 1934-1936
    - Freeman, W. B., 1935
    - Colt, T. C., 1938 (Box 23)
    - “Ga-Gk” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Gaines, F. P., 1934-1935
    - Galt, Sterling, 1934-1935
    - Gillette, C. F., 1935-1936
    - “Gl-Gz” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Glasgow, E., 1934-1936
    - “Haa-Hal” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Hall, Wilmer, 1936
    - Hamlin, P. G., 1936
    - Harrison, F., 1934-1935
    - Hawks, H. E., 1935-1936
    - Hayden, Harry, 1936
    - Hayward, S., 1935
    - “Ham-I” miscellaneous, 1934-1936, (5 folders)
    - Income tax, 1934-1936, (2 folders)
    - “J” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - “Ka-Ln” miscellaneous, 1934-1936, (4 folders) (Box 24)
    - Lee, Robert E.
      - General, 1934-1936, (3 folders)
      - Errors file, 1934-1936, (3 folders)
      - Lee's Lieutenants, 1936
    - Leitz, E. Inc., 1935-1936
    - Lowry, Landon, 1936
    - “Lo-Mb” miscellaneous, 1934-1936, (2 folders)
    - Mackall, L., 1935-1936
    - Malone, D., 1934-1935
    - Maynard and Child, 1937
    - “Mc-Mn” miscellaneous, 1934-1936, (2 folders)
    - Meyer, Wallace, 1934-1936, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Milham, C. G., 1936
    - Mitchell, S. C., 1934-1936
    - “Mo-Mz” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Moore, R. Walton, 1933-1935
    - “N” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Norton, B. W., 1935
    - “O-Ph” miscellaneous, 1934-1936, (2 folders)
    - Peery, George C., 1934-1936
    - Perkins, Maxwell E., 1934-1936, (2 folders)
    - “Pl-Pz” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Pulitzer Prize congratulations, 1935
    - “Ra-Rn” miscellaneous, 1934-1936 (Box 26)
    - Rich, Edgar J., 1935-1936
    - Richmond, University of, 1935-1936
    - “Ro-Rz” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Robertson, A. Willis, 1936
    - Rockefeller, John D., 1934-1936
    - “Sa-Sb” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Saito, Hirosi, 1934-1935
    - Satterfield, Dave E., Jr., 1934-1936
    - “Sc-Sd” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Scribner, Charles, 1934-1936
    - “Se-Sj” miscellaneous, 1935-1936
    - Seay, George J., 1934-1936
    - Sedgwick, Ellery, 1935-1936
    - Shaw, Albert, 1935-1936
    - Sheib, S. H., 1934-1935
    - Shriver, Alfred Jenkins, 1935
    - Sites, Maud Key, 1934-1936
    - “Sk-Sz” miscellaneous, 1934-1936, (2 folders)
    - Stone, Edward L., 1934-1935
    - Stuart, Edward T., 1934
    - Sully, Julia, 1934-1936
    - “T” miscellaneous, 1934-1936 (Box 27)
    - Taylor, Charles H., 1935-1936
    - Taylor, Walter, III, 1934-1935
    - Tax receipts, 1934
    - Turner, Nancy Byrd, 1934
    - “U-V” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Von Boetticher, General Friedrich, 1935-1936
    - “Wa-Wh” miscellaneous, 1934-1936, (2 folders)
    - Weber, William C., 1934-1935
    - Webster, Helen E., 1934-1936
    - Weddell, Alexander W., 1934-1936
    - Wheeler-Bennett, John, 1934-1935
    - Whittaker, Charles E., 1934-1935
    - Whitty, J. H., 1936
    - “Wi-Wz” miscellaneous, 1934-1936
    - Wickham, H. T., 1934-1936
    - Williams (general), 1934-1936
    - Wilmer, Mrs. William H., 1936
    - “X-Z” miscellaneous, 1935-1936
  - 1937-1939 (Box 28)
    - “A” miscellaneous, 1937-1939
    - Ackerman, Carl W., 1937-1939
    - Aldrich, Winthrop W., 1937
    - Armstrong, Donald, 1937
    - Ashworth, Osborne O., 1938-1939
    - Automobile accident, 1938
    - Automobiles, 1937-1939
    - “Ba-Bh” miscellaneous, 1937-1939
    - Barlett, Donald, 1937-1938
    - “Bi-Bq” miscellaneous, 1937-1939
    - Boatwright, Frederick William, 1937-1939
    - Bolling, Mrs. Charles E., 1937-1939
    - Books, 1937-1939
    - Bowman, Isaiah, 1937-1939
    - “Br-Bt” miscellaneous, 1937-1939
    - Brucker, Herbert, 1937-1939
    - Bryan, John Stewart, 1936-1939, (2 folders)
    - “Bu-Bz” miscellaneous, 1937-1939
    - Burne, Alfred H., 1937-1938
    - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1937-1938
    - Byrd, Harry Flood, 1937-1939
    - “Ca-Cg” miscellaneous, 1937-1939 (Box 29)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1938-1939
    - Carter, Howard, 1938 See also same container, Carter, Louise